<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Another Note on A blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>/note/2017/06/14/another-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2017/06/14/another-note/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered an awesome tutorial on blogdown written by Alison. I have to admit this is the best blogdown tutorial I have seen so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Note on Two Beautiful Websites</title>
      <link>/note/2017/06/13/a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2017/06/13/a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description>To me, the two most impressive websites based on blogdown are:
 Rob J Hyndman&amp;rsquo;s personal website. Live Free or Dichotomize by Lucy and Nick et al.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmatory Factor Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/confirmatory-factor-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/confirmatory-factor-analysis/</guid>
      <description>body {font-size: 2em;}IntroductionSimilar to exploratory factor analysis (EFA), confirmatory factor analysis (CFA) is also considered as a common factor model where parameters such as loadings and factorial correlations can be estimated.
The estimation also proceeds by analyzing the constructs and patterns underlying the variance structure of the data (see Table 1)
Also known as covariance structure analysisTable 1: Example Covariance Structure, N = 500y1y2y3y4y5y6y10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factor Analysis and the Exploratory Approach</title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/factor-analysis-and-the-exploratory-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/factor-analysis-and-the-exploratory-approach/</guid>
      <description>body {font-size: 2em;}IntroductionIn the social and behavioral sciences, as well as many other disciplines, researchers often encounter a large set of observations or scores for a group of people or objects.The data can come from any sources of measurement instruments including scale, questionnaire, survey, assessment, and so on.One important question that researchers often want to ask is if the large set of data can be parsimoniously represented with some underlying constructs or patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Path Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/path-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/path-analysis/</guid>
      <description>body {font-size: 2em;}IntroductionPath analysis (PA) is the SEM technique for analyzing structural models with only observed variables (i.e., indicator). Although there are no latent variables (other than the error term), many principles and concepts in PA hold true for more complicated SEM types.
PA can be viewed as an extension of regression analysis
In regression analysis, the variables are either causes or outcomes, with only direct effects in between; moreover, there can be multiple causes for each outcome, but only one outcome for each causeIn PA, the variables can be causes and outcomes at the same time, with both direct and indirect effects available; moreover, multiple causes and multiple outcomes can coexistPA and FA are two building blocks of the SEM family</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Model with Latent Variables</title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/structural-model-with-latent-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/structural-model-with-latent-variables/</guid>
      <description>body {font-size: 2em;}IntroductionThe most general kind of model in SEM is a structural model with latent variables, which is also known as a structural regression (SR) model or full structural equation model (full model)
It can be regarded as a marriage of the path analysis and (confirmatory) factor analysis, and relies on many principles and assumptions under both the PA and CFAThus, a full model can be decomposed into a structural and measurement componentAlthough the coupling of PA and CFA seems straightforward, a full model with both a structural and measurement component can be very complicated, with different combinations of the exogenous and endogenous variables and/or the observed and latent variables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
